Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/janegreenfield (LinkedIn) www.vanguardcharitable.org/home/ (Company) investor.vanguard.com/home/ (Company)

Top Skills

Non-profit Leadership Strategic Planning Talent Management

Certifications

Certified Investment Management Analyst

Honors-Awards

50 Most Powerful Women in U.S. Philanthropy

Jane Greenfield

President at Vanguard Charitable Malvern, Pennsylvania

Summary

Jane Greenfield is president of Vanguard Charitable, a national donor-advised fund and one of the nation's top grantmakers. Prior to joining Vanguard Charitable in 2015, she held a number of positions as a principal at Vanguard in the Institutional, Retail, and Financial divisions. Before joining Vanguard in 2001, Jane spent 16 years in the banking industry. She holds Series 7, 24, 63, and 65 licenses, and the CIMA® designation. In addition, Jane has served on various nonprofit boards, including Bryn Mawr Rehabilitation Hospital, People's Light and Theatre, and United Way Women's Initiative. She earned a B.A. in economics from the College of William and Mary and an M.B.A. from Drexel University.

Experience

Vanguard Charitable
President
July 2015 - Present (5 years 1 month)
Malvern PA

Vanguard Charitable is a leading public charity which sponsors cost-effective donor-advised funds, and is committed to offering a consistently high-quality experience to donors who wish to build a charitable legacy. We firmly believe in the importance of long-term, strategic charitable planning that minimizes costs, and we are proud to offer the highest value donor-advised fund, a claim backed by our low all-in fee and strong alignment with the time-tested principles of Vanguard, a leader in at-cost investments.

As President, Jane leads one of the largest grantmaking organizations with over 9 billion in grants issued since inception, as well as being one of the largest sponsors of donor-advised funds in the United States. She continually drives innovation and growth in an everchanging philanthropic landscape. Jane oversees the organization's philanthropic strategy, providing strong and compassionate leadership to her teams. She is a true culture leader at

Vanguard Charitable ensuring that the charitable mission is always front and center.

Vanguard

14 years 2 months

Principal of High Net Worth Advice

August 2014 - June 2015 (11 months)

Malvern PA

Managed the Advice group for our clients with \$1 million or more in investable assets, plus the Trust Company.

Principal of Defined Contribution Investment Business

August 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Malvern PA

Managed Vanguard's DC Investment business, working with Plan Sponsors of all sizes across the Nation.

Principal - Institutional Client Services

January 2009 - July 2012 (3 years 7 months)

Malvern PA

Managed a Team of professionals responsible for some of our largest Defined Contribution Plan Sponsor clients.

Principal of Institutional Client Administration

September 2006 - December 2008 (2 years 4 months)

Malvern PA

Responsible for the team of professionals tasked with administering Defined Contribution Plans for our Institutional clients across the nation.

Principal - Center for Excellence

January 2006 - September 2006 (9 months)

Malvern PA

Responsible for a team of Six Sigma Black Belts charged with serving Vanguard's Institutional business.

Principal - Institutional Client Services

May 2003 - December 2005 (2 years 8 months)

Malvern PA

Responsible for a team of Relationship Managers who manage some of the largest Institutional clients.

Senior Manager - Financial Division

May 2001 - May 2003 (2 years 1 month)

Page 2 of 3

Malvern PA

Managed the Bank Strategy group, and was responsible for creating a strategy for working with bank partners, managing RFPs for changing partners, and taking the group through change to manage bank relationships more strategically.

Mellon Bank
First Vice President Wealth Management
May 1999 - May 2001 (2 years 1 month)
Philadelphia PA

Managed the Private Banking business in Philadelphia.

CoreStates Bank / First Union Various September 1985 - April 1999 (13 years 8 months) Philadelphia PA

Various positions over 14 years in the Institutional side of the Bank, including Relationship Manager, Department Head of high-growth developmental markets, Strategic Marketing, and Large Corporate.

Education

Drexel University

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Finance, General · (1988 - 1992)

William and Mary
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Economics · (1981 - 1985)

Agnes Irwin School High School · (1975 - 1981)